Caitlin Bruni

215-593-5666

45 Goldenrod Ct. Hamilton, NJ, 08690

Objective: To obtain a position as an elementary School Teacher that will utilize my strong dedication to children's development and to their educational needs.

Summary

Professional educator dedicated to the total development of children through the utilization of sound planning strategies and lesson implementations. Key skills include:

*Classroom design and behavior management and curriculum design
*Writing and implementing appropriate Instructional Educational Plans and lesson plans
*Interventions

*Collaboration (parents/legal guardians as well as staff)

*Assessments and data taking

*Differentiated Instruction

Pennsylvania Certified: Instructional II Elementary Education K-6, Instructional II Special Education N-21, Instructional II Reading Specialist

Education

Cabrini College, Radnor PA

Masters in Education with Reading Specialist Certification + 30

May 2013

GPA 3.85

Gwynedd-Mercy College, Gwynedd Valley PA

Bachelor of Science in Special Education

May 2009

- PA certified in Elementary and Special Education
- Cumulative GPA:3.74- Magna Cum Laude

Honors:

- Josephine C. Connelly Scholarship
- Kappa Delta Distinguished Student Award
- Dean's List

Related Work History

St. Paul School in Burlington City, NJ March 2016- Present

Fourth Grade Teacher- Instructing students in all core subjects in 4th Grade curriculum. Providing students with an encouraging and enjoyable learning environment. Taking attendance, evaluating assignments, and preserving a structured learning environment. Monitoring student progress and conducting consistent assessments, adjusting lessons to meet individual needs of students. Communicating extensively with parents and regularly scheduled parent-teacher conferences.

Ad Prima Charter School 2015

December 2014December

Kindergarten and Firt Grade Teacher- I was responsible for instructing Kindergarteners. I worked diligently to prepare and implement lesson plans, worked as a team member, helped create a therapeutic classroom environment, professionally communicated with peers and families, as well as differentiated my instruction to meet the needs of the students.

Kelly Educational Staffing I was a building substitute.

King of Prussia,PAOctober 2014-December 2014

Main Street Elementary School

Upland, PA

4th Grade Teacher

September 2014-Oct 2014

I was responsible for instructing students in an elementary school from grade 4. Created lesson plans, administered praise and constructive criticism, instructed students on subjects such as science, literature, and math, and created a well-rounded, comprehensive instructional program.

Prodigy Learning Academy

Philadelphia, PA

Language Arts Teacher (Grades 1-5)

September 2013-August 2014

• I designed Common Core Language Arts Curriculum for Grades 1-5, taught Language Arts Curriculum to students in grades 1-5, collaborated and held conferences with parents and legal guardians, participated in staff development meetings/trainings, helped supervise the Physical Education Teacher, was the Second Grade homeroom teacher, worked in the Before and After Care

Devereux (Day School)

Downingtown, PA

Head Autistic Support Teacher

May 2012- August 2013

 Designed and implemented Instructional Education Plans for children with autism, analyzed data, participated in Professional Developments, ran classroom meetings, taught vocational and life skills

Private Family

Malvern, PA

2013- Currently

Tutor a child with Asperger's in his fifth grade curriculum, plan and supervise social activities, provide additional educational lessons and assessments

Green Tree School

Philadelphia, PA

Head Autistic Support Teacher

September 2009 – May 2012

 Designed and implemented Instructional Education Plans for children with autism, analyzed data, participated in Professional Developments, ran classroom meetings, was an active member of the Safety Committee, designed and implemented lesson plans, helped with job training, curriculum design, Community Based Instructional Planning Taught and assessed an individual with special in needs life skills

Montgomery County Intermediate Unit

Norristown, PA 2008 – 2009

Substitute Aid

• Aided the head teacher with any educational responsibilities (performed pareducator responsibilities when the paradeducator was absent)

Campus and Community Involvement

- ♦ Kappa Delta Pi, **President**, 2008 present
- ♦ Best Buddies Executive Officer
- Gwynedd Mercy Association of Education for Young Children Executive Officer
- ♦ Math Club President 2007-2008
- ◆ ASD/ Early Childhood Safety Committee Representative, September 2009-May 2012
- ♦ Service Trip to Arizona
 - Taught Native Americans with special needs

Professional Development and Trainings

- ◆ Adult CPR/AED, Child CPR and First Aid, Pediatric First Aid
- ◆ PECS training and corrective approach to PECS
- ♦ ABA training
- ♦ Indicator 13 IEP training
- ♦ Effectively Educating Students with Autism (14 hour training course)
- ♦ Behavioral Implementation Training
- ♦ Data Collection Training
- ♦ Environmental Education Training
- ♦ Life Skills Coach Training
- ♦ Community Building Training
- Understanding Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder training
- ◆ Leadership certificates for KDP